A Guide to the Business Records of the Hogshead-Smiley Mill, 1807-1901
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Business Records of the Hogshead-Smiley Mill 1807-1901
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
38-22
The Hogshead-Smiley Mill Records consist of 37 items, ca. 1807-1901, and seven ledgers.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The collection was purchased from Mrs. Richard Hogshead, Middlebrook, Virginia, 1 January 1935.
Alternative Form Available
Account book of Smiley's Mill, 1807-1827 and Account Ledger of "T. M. Smiley's Mill," 1891-1901 are also available on microfilm M-2405.
Scope and Content
The Hogshead-Smiley Mill Records consist of 37 items, ca. 1807-1901, and seven ledgers, 1846-1912. The papers are chiefly deeds for land around the mill, on Moffats Creek in Augusta County, Virginia. Also included is an unbound account book of Smiley's Mill, ca. 1807-1827. The ledgers consist of grist mill accounts kept by John R. Robinson, E.A. Lacy, and others, millers for William Smiley.
Contents List
- Account book of Smiley's Mill 1807-1827
- Land deeded between Jane & Robert McChesney, Sr. & Robert McChesney 1808
- Land deeded between Samuel Clarke & Robert McChesney, Sr. 1812 Sep
- Land deeded between James & May McClums; William, Jane & John McChesney & Robert McChesney 1816 May 18
- Land deeded between James & Jane Buchanan & Robert McChesney 1822 Apr 19
- Land deeded between Robert McChesney & John McChesney 1823 Feb 24
- Land located for Robert McChesney by John Page 1826 Jun 3; Aug 26
- Land deeded between William Cales & Robert McChesney 1842 Jun 9
- Land surveyed for Robert McChesney by John Withrow 1842 Jun
- Land deeded between William Cales & John Cales 1842 Jul 30
- Land surveyed for John Cales by John Withrow 1845 Oct 31
- Land surveyed for Elijah Hogshead by James M. Lilley 1846 Dec 3
- Sale of land - Elijah Hogshead (Exr of Wm. Cales) to Robert McChesney 1847 Mar 15
- Land deeded between Elijah Hogshead (Exr of Wm. Cales) & Robert McChesney 1847 Jun 28
- Land deeded between Samuel & Jane Seroul & John C. Echard 1849 May 26
- Extract from deed - William Brubeck 1850 Sep 7
- Land deeded between Daniel & Mary Hull & James F. Hite 1853
- Survey of land, Joseph Lowman 1853 May 31
- Land deeded between Daniel & Mary Hull & Robert Craig, James F. Hite, & D.C. Arehart 1857 Mar 21
- Land surveyed for Robert McChesney & John N. Hite by James H. Callison 1859 Apr
- Land deeded between Robert McChesney & John N. Hite 1859 Sep 13
- Land deeded between J.C. Echard & Samuel Payne 1860 Dec 24
- Land deeded between John & Elizabeth Echard & James F. Hite 1865 Oct 31
- Land surveyed for Robert Craig & John N. Hite by Jas. H. Callison 1872 Mar 1
- Land deeded between James F. Hite & John N. Hite 1874 Oct 23
- Land deeded between T.C. Rice Brubeck, Robert B. Brubeck & Amanda Brubeck & John N. Hite 1881 Sep 21
- Land deeded between Henry C. Hite & John N. Hite 1882 Dec 5
- Land deeded between John Weir & John H. Hite 1894 Jan 30
- Land deeded between John & Elizabeth Hite & Henry C. Hite 1894 Feb 12
- Land deeded between Jane & John R. Mines & John N. Hite 1894 Aug 13
- Land deeded between James Bumgardner, Jr.; Fitzhugh Elder: Trustees of William H. Wilson & John N. Hite 1901 May 7
- Misc. papers ca. 1807-1901
- Ledgers
  - Index. Tables showing tolls received, wheat sowed and harvested, part produced, etc. 1846 [1852-1864] 1912, 1
  - Index 1854-1860, 2
  - Index 1860-1868, 3
  - Index. Special accounts of tolls on William Smiley's & J.B. Schultz's grain 1869-1875, 4
  - No index. Chiefly for Abarrel "accounts" 1876-1888, 5
  - Index 1880-1891, 6
  - Account Ledger of "T. M. Smiley's Mill" (183 pages w/ [partial] index) 1891-1901, 7
  - James Miller and William Miller - land deeded to William Gale 1811 Oct 22
  - Land grant to Robert McChesney 1840 Nov 3
  - Harvey Paine and wife - land deeded to Robert McChesney 1842 Oct 4